RG 009, Office of the Attorney General
Connecticut State Library
- Series 3. Subject Files, bulk
  - T002854, 0.5 cubic feet
    - Taxes - inheritance, Federal - publications, 1926 (Box 5)
    - Taxes - property - churches, Branford, 1928 (Box 5)
    - Veterans - World War I - adjusted compensation, 1923-1927 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous items, circa 1927-1931, undated (Box 5)
      Folder contains a brochure listing photographs for sale, Addison C. Getchell and Son legal printers parcel card, a magazine offer from the American Medical Association, a diary of appointments, and a volume of Connecticut Motor Vehicle Laws.
  - 1984-094, cubic feet
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1919-1929; 2 folders and 2 accordian files (Box 31)
      Folder contains lists of General Assembly bills, public acts, and special acts by topic; notes; and an Attorney General opinion, correspondence, and lists of public acts effected by the McCook decision.
    - First Report of the Judicial Council of Connecticut, created by Chapter 190, General Statutes 1927., 1928 November (Box 31)
    - Matter for Board of Control, 1935-1937 (Box 36)
    - Law, 1934-1936 (Box 36)
      Folder contains correspondence, Comptroller statements and studies, and Emergency Relief Administration pay rolls for personal services.
    - Evidence, circa 1935-1939 (Box 36)
      Folder contains a compiled volume of rulings of the Board of Finance and Control, statements, and photostat copies of Emergency Relief Administration pay rolls for personal services.
    - Clap estate, 1921 (Box 36)
    - Bank files, 1933-1937 (Box 36)
    - Fairfield County Commissioners, 1936 (Box 36)
    - Bonds - state officers and employees, 1935-1936 (Box 36)
    - New Haven Water Company, circa 1933 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1935-1936 (Box 36)
      Folder contains "Minutes. Meeting of Sub-Committee in RE: Fairfield State Hospital, Newtown"; correspondence; notes; appropriation figures; and hearing transcript on H.B. 891 concering Connecticut's Tercentenary.
    - Examination of Statutes on Bonds of State Officials, 1936 (Box 36)
    - Bills, 1907-1910 (Box 36)
    - Bills, 1928 (Box 36)
    - Bonds, circa 1903-1904, undated (Box 36)
    - Estimate of expenses, 1904 (Box 36)
    - Legislation, circa 1903-1905 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous, 1903, undated (Box 36)
      Folder consists of correspondence from the Reformatory Commission; a blank State of Connecticut Certificate of Examining Committee of The Connecticut Eclectic Medical Association; a blank Board of Veterinary Registration and Examination application; The Equitable Home Assurance Company contract form; court calendars; receipts; and notes.
    - School Fund Department, 1912-1914 (Box 36)
    - Board of Finance - meeting number 39 minutes, 1924 February 7 (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1894-1895; 2 folders (Box 37)
      Folders consist of correspondence, invoices, receipts, and notes.
    - American Bonding and Trust Company of Baltimore City, 1899 (Box 38)
    - Corporations that have failed to make returns within the legal period, 1880-April 30, 1901, circa 1901 (Box 38)
- Subgroup 4. Connecticut vs. Massachusetts, 1890-1932; bulk 1928-1934
  Inventory of Connecticut vs. Massachusetts Records
- Subgroup 5. Francis A. Pallotti vs. William J. Cox, 1942
  Inventory of Francis A. Pallotti vs. William J. Cox Records
- Subgroup 6. Abele vs. Markle, 1947-1981
  Inventory of Abele vs. Markle Records
- Subgroup 7. Indian Litigation Files, 1666-2008; bulk 1965-2008
  Inventory of Indian Litigation Files
- Series 8. Opinions, 1899-1971
  - T002854, 1.5 cubic feet
    - Opinions re: local taxes, 1934-1971; 7 folders (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous opinions, 1903-1927 (Box 7)
      - Opinion re: banks and banking, 1903-1913 (Box 7)
      - Opinion Connecticut National Guard re: employers release to attend annual camp, 1927 (Box 7)
      - Opinion Long Lane School re: authority to sign underage marriage applications, 1927 (Box 7)
      - Opinion State Board of Education re: reimbursement of school expenses by Children Aid Society, 1927 (Box 7)
      - Opinion State Board of Education re: right to free education by residents of Hillcrest Farm School, 1927 (Box 7)
      - Opinions - written summaries of verbal opinions, 1930 (Box 7)
  - 1984-094
    - Opinions, circa 1899-1902; 11 folders (Box 35)
    - Opinions, circa 1903-1905, undated; 1 folder (Box 36)
- Series 9. Press Releases, 1983-1990
  - 2002-063, 1 cubic foot
    - Lieberman, Joseph press releases, 1983-1989 (Box 1)
    - Riddle, Clarine Nardi press releases, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
- Series 10. Corporation Penalty Letters, 1908-1949
  - 1984-087, 9.5 cubic feet
    - Correspondence, 1908-1949
      - A-Z, 1908-1911 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
      - A-J, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
      - K-Z, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
      - A-Z, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 3-8)
      - List of Corporations failing to file reports for two or more years, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - A-N, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
      - O-Z, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
      - A-Z, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
      - A-M, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 8-11)
      - N-Z, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
      - A-Z, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 3-8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1925-1926, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Secretary of State late Annual Company Reports, circa 1927 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - A-Q, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 11-16)
      - R-Z, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      - A-Z, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - A-Z, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 4-9)
      - A-F, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 10-14)
      - G-Z, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 1-11)
      - A-H, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 1-9)
      - J-Z, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
      - A-Z, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 6-12)
      - A-D, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 1-8)
      - E-K, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 1-10)
      - L-R, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 1-12)
      - S-Z, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 1-12)
      - List of Corporations failing to file reports for two or more years, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - A-Z, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
      - A-L, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 3-9)
      - M-Z, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 1-7)
      - List of Corporations failing to file reports for two or more years, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - A-H, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 9-13)
      - I-Z, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
      - A-Z, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 7-14)
      - A-Z, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - A-Z, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 2-4)
      - A-Z, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - A-L, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 6-12)
      - M-Z, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 1-6)
      - A-G, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 7-11)
      - H-Z, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 1-9)
      - A-Z, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1919-1949 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - 1984-093, 3 cubic feet
    - Penalty Letters, 1928-1930
      - 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 1-22)
      - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1-22)
      - 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1-21)
      - 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 1-22)
      - 1929 (Box 5, Folder 1-22)
      - 1929-1930 (Box 6, Folder 1-12)
- Series 11. Blueprints and Maps
- Series 12. Highway Department Reports of Accidents, 1917-1922
  - 1984-087, 1 cubic foot
    - B-H, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
    - M-O, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 7-10)
    - R-T, V-W, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
    - A-O, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 1-7)
    - R-T, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - W, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - B, 1920 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - D-E, 1921 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - M-N, 1921 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - R, 1922 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Series 13. Workmen's Compensation Case Files, circa 1936-1962
  RESTRICTED
  Conn. Gen. Stat. sec. 1-210(b)(2) of the Freedom of Information Act exempts from disclosure personnel or medical files and similar files the disclosure of which would constitute an invasion of personal privacy. Conn. Gen. Stat. sec. 1-210(b)(10) of the Freedom of Information Act exempts from disclosure any records created as a result of a doctor-patient or a therapist-patient relationship.
  - T000107, 55 cubic feet
    - A-B, circa 1936-1959 (Box 1)
      Files arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - Payment lists, 1953-1959; 14 folders (Box 2)
    - Hearing notices, 1953-1958; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - C, circa 1936-1959 (Box 2A)
    - D-E, circa 1936-1959 (Box 3)
    - F-G, circa 1936-1959 (Box 4)
    - H, J-K, circa 1936-1959 (Box 5)
    - L-M, circa 1936-1959 (Box 6)
    - M-P, circa 1936-1959 (Box 7)
    - P-S, circa 1936-1959 (Box 8)
    - S, circa 1936-1959 (Box 9)
    - T-Z, circa 1936-1959 (Box 10)
    - Adjutant General's Dept.-Forestry Dept., circa 1936-1959 (Box 11)
      Files arranged alphabetically by agency.
    - Governor's Office-Mansfield Training School and Hospital, circa 1936-1959 (Box 12)
    - Military Dept.-Water Commission, circa 1936-1959 (Box 13)
    - Fitch's Home for Soldiers, 1939-1953 (Box 14)
      Files arranged chronologically.
    - State Police claims, 1947-1949; 1 folder (Box 15)
      Cancellation of uncollectible accounts for damages caused to state cars as approved by Governor Ribicoff on November 2, 1956.
    - State Police, 1939-1947 (Box 15)
    - Collections property damage (all agencies except State Police), 1952-1953 (Box 16)
    - Uncollectibles State Police, 1952, 1956 (Box 16)
    - State Police claims and uncollectibles, 1950-1952 (Box 16)
    - State Police-reports-property damage, 1944-1953 (Box 16)
    - State Police-unpaid, 1949-1950 (Box 16)
    - State Police damages (uncollectible), 1944-1949 (Box 16)
    - State Police uncollectible, 1951-1952 (Box 16)
    - State Police workers compensation files, 1951-1953; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - State Police paid, 1951 (Box 16)
    - State Police paid, 1949 (Box 16)
    - State Police workers compensation files, 1949-1951 (Box 16)
    - State Police accidents - paid, 1947-1950 (Box 16)
    - State Police - paid, 1949-1950 (Box 16)
    - Fairfield State Hospital (inactive), 1939-1950; 12 folders (Box 17)
    - Fairfield State Hospital (inactive), 1950-1953; 8 folders (Box 18)
    - Norwich State Hospital (inactive), 1939-1948; 12 folders (Box 19)
    - Norwich State Hospital (inactive), 1948-1953; 16 folders (Box 20)
    - Connecticut State Hospital (inactive), 1939-1948; 12 folders (Box 21)
    - Connecticut State Hospital (inactive), 1948-1953; 11 folders (Box 22)
    - Norwich State Hospital, A-Z, circa 1948-1956 (Box 23)
      Files arranged alphabetically by first or last name and include a case number.
    - Norwich State Hospital, B-W, circa 1953-1956 (Box 23A)
    - Highway Department, A-K, circa 1950-1958 (Box 24)
    - Highway Department, L-Z, circa 1950-1958 (Box 25)
    - Fairfield State Hospital, A-Z, circa 1949-1957 (Box 26)
    - Fairfield State Hospital, A-W, circa 1949-1957 (Box 26A)
    - Connecticut State College (inactive), 1939-1941 (Box 27)
    - University of Connecticut, 1941-1945 (Box 27)
    - University of Connecticut (inactive), 1945-1953; 5 folders (Box 27)
    - State Parks and Forest Commission (inactive), 1939-1942; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Park and Forest Commission, 1942-1948 (Box 27)
    - Park and Forest Commission (inactive), 1948-1952; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Highway Department index of cases, 1937-1938 (Box 28)
    - Highway Department (inactive), 1947 October-1949 May; 20 folders (Box 28)
    - Highway Department (inactive), 1949 June-1953 June; 49 folders (Box 29)
    - Highway Department, A-K, circa 1952-1959 (Box 30)
    - Highway Department, L-Z, circa 1952-1959 (Box 31)
    - State Police closed third party, A-G, circa 1951-1960 (Box 32)
    - State Police closed third party, H-M, circa 1951-1960 (Box 33)
    - Highway Department closed third party, A-W, circa 1955-1960 (Box 33A)
    - State Police closed third party, M-Z, circa 1953-1960 (Box 34)
    - Agricultural Experiment Station, A-W, 1953-1956; 12 folders (Box 35)
    - Department of Health, L, P, S, 1954; 4 folders (Box 35)
    - Labor Department, B, F, H, M, R, T, U, 1954-1956; 11 folders (Box 35)
    - Department of Education, B-C, F-H, K-M, P, R-S, W, Y, 1953-1956; 27 folders (Box 35)
    - Veterans Home and Hospital, B-H, J-K, M, O-P, R-W, circa 1953-1958; 73 folders (Box 35)
    - Agricultural Experiment Station, B-D, G, M-N, R, T, 1953-1955; 12 folders (Box 36)
    - Department of Health, A-B, D-G, K-M, O-P, R-T, W, 1945-1956; 25 folders (Box 36)
    - Labor Department, A-D, F, H, K, M, P, S, Y, 1949-1955; 20 folders (Box 36)
    - Department of Education, A-D, F-H, K, M-P, T, 1941-1955; 28 folders (Box 36)
    - Veterans Home and Hospital, A-D, F-H, J-K, M-P, R-T, W, circa 1945-1955; 68 folders (Box 36)
    - State Park and Forest Commission, B-H, J-M, P, R-T, V-W, circa 1939-1957; 54 folders (Box 37)
    - University of Connecticut, A-D, G-H, K, M, P, S-T, W, 1940-1960; 27 folders (Box 37)
    - Uncas on Thames, A-E, G-H, K-M, P, S, W, Z, 1945-1957; 21 folders (Box 37)
    - Undercliff Sanatorium, B, D-E, G-H, L-N, P, R-S, W, 1950-1957; 16 folders (Box 37)
    - State Park and Forest Commission, B-H, K-M, P, R-T, V-W, circa 1953-1956; 54 folders (Box 38)
    - University of Connecticut, A-D, G-H, K-M, P, S, W, Y, circa 1954-1957; 32 folders (Box 38)
    - Uncas on Thames, A-D, G, I, K-L, N, R, 1954-1956; 17 folders (Box 38)
    - Undercliff Sanatorium, A-B, F, H, J-K, M, O-P, S, 1953-1958; 21 folders (Box 38)
    - Connecticut State Hospital, B-H, J-P, R-T, V-W, Z, circa 1953-1957; 126 folders (Box 39)
    - State Welfare Department, A-D, G, L, N, P, Q, S, 1948-1957; 16 folders (Box 39)
    - Motor Vehicle Department, B-D, F-H, J-M, P, S, 1938-1955; 19 folders (Box 39)
    - Connecticut State Hospital, A-H, J-M, P, R-T, V-W, Z, circa 1944-1959; 150 folders (Box 39A)
    - State Welfare Department, A-C, F, M, P, T, 1954-1957; 9 folders (Box 39A)
    - Motor Vehicle Department, B, E-F, K, M, 1954-1955; 5 folders (Box 39A)
    - Comptroller - Bills, etc. referred for payment. All Depts. except highway, 1949 (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - Bills fwd. (All Depts. except highway), 1950 (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - Bills fwd. (All Depts. except highway), 1950 (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - Bills for Highway Dept. only, 1949 (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - Bills fwd (Highway Dept.), 1950 (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - Bills fwd (Highway Dept.), 1951 (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - Bills fwd all depts. except highway, 1951 (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - (Bills fwd - Highway Dept.), 1952 January-June (Box 40)
    - Comptroller - (Bills fwd - all depts. except highway), 1952 (Box 40)
    - Highway (Bills), 1952-1953 (Box 40)
    - Lists of payments on compensation, 1952 (Box 40)
    - Transmittal letters re bills, etc. to Comptrollers, 1952 July-1953 June (Box 40)
    - State Police paid, 1952-1953; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Uncollectable State Police claims, 1947-1949 (Box 41)
    - Log book, 1940-1956; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Log books, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Log books, 1949-1959; 4 folders (Box 41)
    - Conscientious objectors (compensation cases), 1943-1951 (Box 41)
    - Bills - not paid (torn shirts, etc.), 1945-1951 (Box 41)
    - Form 15 completed, 1943-1950 (Box 41)
    - Waivers (all departments and institutions), circa 1944-1952 (Box 41)
    - Southbury Training School, A-J, L-M, P-W, circa 1947-1959; 78 folders (Box 42)
    - State Tax Department, A-C, H, L-M, S, 1951-1960; 8 folders (Box 42)
    - Connecticut Agriculture Department, C, F-G, M, W, 1949-1958; 5 folders (Box 42)
    - Department of Aeronautics, A-D, F-H, K-M, P, R-V, 1950-1958; 31 folders (Box 42)
    - Public Works Department, A-D, F, H, L-M, R, Z, 1951-1955; 17 folders (Box 42)
    - List of names, undated; 1 page (Box 43)
    - Cedarcrest Sanatorium, B-C, F-G, I, K-M, P, R-S, W, 1944-1958; 23 folders (Box 43)
    - Seaside Sanatorium, A, D, G-H, J, L, R-S, U, W, 1943-1955; 13 folders (Box 43)
    - Mansfield Training School, A-D, G, L-N, P, R-T, V-W, circa 1940-1955; 43 folders (Box 43)
    - Civil Defense, B-D, H, K-M, R-U, W, 1952-1960; 22 folders (Box 44)
    - Attorney General, F, 1953-1955; 1 folder (Box 44)
    - Connecticut Marketing Authority, S, 1954; 1 folder (Box 44)
    - Liquor Control Commission, T, 1955; 1 folder (Box 44)
    - Food and Drug Commission, C, W, 1954; 2 folders (Box 44)
    - State Alcoholic Commission, D, L, S, 1952-1959; 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Wethersfield State Prison, A, C, F-G, J, 1948-1954; 7 folders (Box 44)
    - Fish and Game, A-B, G-H, P, R, S, W, 1950-1960; 15 folders (Box 44)
    - Connecticut School for Boys, A, E, G, L-M, R-S, W, 1948-1956; 11 folders (Box 44)
    - Laurel Heights, A-C, H, K-M, O, R-S, V, W, Z, 1951-1958; 20 folders (Box 44)
    - Finance and Control, B, S, 1953-1955; 4 folders (Box 44)
    - Commission on the Care and Treatment of the Chronically Ill, Aged, and Infirm, C-E, M, S, 1953-1955; 5 folders (Box 44)
    - Connecticut Judicial Department, C, E-F, L-M, P, R, 1952-1955; 11 folders (Box 44)
      Contains 8 folders for Connecticut State Library employees and 3 folders for Connecticut Judicial Department employees.
    - Long Lane School, B-C, F, H, M, S, W, 1952-1956; 14 folders (Box 44)
    - Connecticut Reformatory, D, L, S-T, 1954-1955; 4 folders (Box 44)
    - State Farm for Women, A-C, F, M, R, 1952-1955; 7 folders (Box 44)
    - Highway Department, A-H, J-P, R-T, V-W, Z, circa 1950-1958 (Box 45)
    - Connecticut State Hospital, A-N, P-W, Z, circa 1953-1958 (Box 46)
    - Fairfield State Hospital, A-H, J-P, R-T, V-W, circa 1953-1959 (Box 47)
    - Norwich State Hospital, A-D, F-H, J-P, R-T, W, circa 1953-1959 (Box 48)
    - University of Connecticut, B-D, G-I, K, M, P, R-T, W, circa 1954-1958; 30 folders (Box 48)
    - Mansfield Training School, A-F, L-M, P, R, T, W, 1954-1957; 19 folders (Box 49)
    - State Park and Forest Commission, B-D, F-G, I-L, N, P, R-S, V-W, Y-Z, circa 1948-1957; 61 folders (Box 49)
    - Veterans Home and Hospital, A-D, F-M, P-S, W, circa 1953-1960; 54 folders (Box 49)
    - State Department of Education, A-E, G-H, J-N, P, R-T, V-W, circa 1955-1958; 46 folders (Box 49)
    - Southbury Training School, B-D, G-H, K-M, R-T, W, 1955-1956; 23 folders (Box 49)
    - Uncas on Thames, D-E, H, L-M, T, 1954-1961; 12 folders (Box 50)
    - State Welfare Department, B-C, H, K-L, P, R-T, 1955-1962; 15 folders (Box 50)
    - Department of Health, A-C, E-F, K-M, O-P, S-T, W, 1954-1957; 19 folders (Box 50)
    - State Department of Labor, C-D, F-H, K-M, R-S, W, 1955-1957; 16 folders (Box 50)
    - Undercliff Hospital, B, L, O, R, 1955-1957; 5 folders (Box 50)
    - Motor Vehicle Department, B-C, F, H, T, 1955-1958; 9 folders (Box 50)
    - Long Lane School, O, S, 1944-1958; 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Public Works Department, A, C, J, M, 1952-1957; 9 folders (Box 50)
    - Agricultural Experiment Station, F, P, Y-Z, 1954-1956; 5 folders (Box 50)
    - Laurel Heights Sanatorium, F-G, V, 1955-1956; 4 folders (Box 50)
    - Cedarcrest Hospital, B, F, H, L, O, S, 1953-1956; 9 folders (Box 50)
    - State Farm for Women, A-B, M-N, R-S, 1955-1957; 13 folders (Box 50)
    - Department of Aeronautics, D, F, H, L, S, W, Z, 1955-1956; 8 folders (Box 50)
    - Wethersfield State Prison, C, K, S-T, 1955-1956; 5 folders (Box 50)
    - Civil Defense, A-C, H, M-N, R-T, 1951-1958; 11 folders (Box 50)
    - Board of Fisheries and Game, B, G-H, J, W, 1952-1961; 5 folders (Box 50)
    - Connecticut Reformatory, B, D, 1954-1956; 3 folders (Box 50)